<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://docs.chasoft.net/blog</id>
    <title>Chasoft Labs Blog</title>
    <updated>2022-08-26T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://docs.chasoft.net/blog"/>
    <subtitle>Chasoft Labs Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://docs.chasoft.net/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Ari your choice to start a personal website]]></title>
        <id>is-ari-your-choice-to-start-a-personal-website</id>
        <link href="https://docs.chasoft.net/blog/is-ari-your-choice-to-start-a-personal-website"/>
        <updated>2022-08-26T12:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[Ari is special, and it is really not fit for everyone. Ari is not a WYSIWYG and you must work with a bit of coding and learning something new as reading some basic TypeScript code and following some instructions. In my previous blog post Why you should have a personal website?, the reason #2, you must be the type of people who love to learn and experiment new things. In case you are not, but you still want… to have a powerful personal website based on Ari, contact me and I will do it for you as a service.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ari is special, and it is really not fit for everyone. Ari is not a WYSIWYG and you must work with a bit of coding and learning something new as reading some basic TypeScript code and following some instructions. In my previous blog post <a href="/blog/why-you-should-have-a-personal-website">Why you should have a personal website?</a>, <a href="/blog/why-you-should-have-a-personal-website#acquire-new-skills">the reason #2</a>, you must be the type of people who love to learn and experiment new things. In case you are not, but you still want… <!-- -->to have a powerful personal website based on Ari, <a href="/docs/addons-services">contact me</a> and I will do it for you as a service.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-ari-benefits-you">What Ari benefits you?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-ari-benefits-you" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="running-ari-is-free">Running Ari is Free<a class="hash-link" href="#running-ari-is-free" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><p>Yes, running Ari is <strong>completely FREE</strong>, <code>No Hosting Cost</code>. Or to be professional, you can also buy a domain for your personal website from Cloudflare <em>(Cloudflare is the first and the best place where you can buy domains with original price, no surplus charging)</em></p><h3 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="powerful-website-">Powerful website 💪<a class="hash-link" href="#powerful-website-" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h3><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="for-you">For you<a class="hash-link" href="#for-you" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><p>Can <code>express</code> any type of information that you want:</p><ul><li>You can write <strong>blog posts</strong></li><li>You can showcase your <strong>portfolios</strong> with the world</li><li>You can have any <strong>announcements</strong> <em>(yes, if you want to announce something, and you want your visitor knows)</em></li><li>You can have some <strong>notes</strong> <em>(yes, it's not an announcement, it cannot be a blog post, it is just a note… likes your thinking, and you just want to share to the world)</em></li><li>You can have <strong>updates</strong> <em>(like a kind of notifications)</em> and to let the world knows about.</li></ul><p>Acquire <strong>new skills</strong>:</p><ul><li>Working with <strong>codes</strong> to build the appearance of your website</li><li>Learn new ways of <strong>conveying</strong> your message</li><li>Learn how to <strong>craft the content</strong> that tells everyone what you're all about</li><li>Learn how to be more visible on social media and how to <strong>promote</strong> your site <em>(basic of <strong>SEO</strong>)</em></li></ul><h4 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="for-your-visitors">For your visitors<a class="hash-link" href="#for-your-visitors" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h4><ul><li>Feel <strong>comfortable</strong> for the website is <strong>blazing fast</strong>.</li><li>Feel <strong>happy</strong> for they can <strong>search/filter/browsing</strong> any type of information the easy way.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-ari-need-you-to-do">What Ari need you to do?<a class="hash-link" href="#what-ari-need-you-to-do" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li>Eager to <strong>learn/explore new things</strong></li><li><strong>Time</strong> to spend with Ari</li></ul><p>or you just need:</p><ul><li>Be willing to <strong>spend money</strong> to <strong><a href="/docs/addons-services#customization">hire me</a></strong> to do the service for you, which, based on Ari. Some basic activities, I would do via remote to let you have chances to learn/explore new things.</li></ul><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="what-to-do-next">What to do next<a class="hash-link" href="#what-to-do-next" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><ul><li><a href="http://store.chasoft.net/l/ari-elegant-and-powerful-serverless-website" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Purchase a license of Ari</a></li><li>Read following articles:<ul><li><a href="/docs/ari/getting-started/faqs">FAQs</a> &gt; <code>I get lost, I don't know what to do!</code></li><li><a href="/docs/ari/advanced-guides/files-structure">Files structure</a></li></ul></li><li>Ask for support <a href="mailto:support@chasoft.net" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">via email</a> or subscribe for <a href="https://store.chasoft.net/l/telegram-support-channel-for-ari" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Telegram Support Channel for Ari</a> if you would rather not wait for any of your support requests.</li></ul>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Cao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/chasoft</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="ari" term="ari"/>
        <category label="serverless website" term="serverless website"/>
        <category label="personal website" term="personal website"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why you should have a personal website?]]></title>
        <id>why-you-should-have-a-personal-website</id>
        <link href="https://docs.chasoft.net/blog/why-you-should-have-a-personal-website"/>
        <updated>2022-08-26T11:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[There are so many articles out there, for many years, and many people still don't realize the benefits of having a personal website. I did research on Google and found many articles talk about this topic. I read them all. Likewise, I agree with all what they have written. And I did a summary for your reference. Let's go ✈.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There are so many articles out there, for many years, and many people still don't realize the benefits of having a personal website. I did research on Google and found many articles talk about this topic. I read them all. Likewise, I agree with all what they have written. And I did a summary for your reference. Let's go ✈.</p><p>A ✨ curated list ✨ of benefits or purposes of having a personal website:</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="easier-to-find-a-job"><strong>1. Easier to find a job</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#easier-to-find-a-job" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Recruiters find you much more easily, they understand who you are, what you are doing, and you did making a great first impression, will help you secure an interview. Sure, this would be one of your competitive advantage.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="acquire-new-skills"><strong>2. Acquire new skills</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#acquire-new-skills" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><blockquote><p>Once you start working on creating a personal website, you'll see what works for you and what doesn't. You'll keep customizing and polishing your personal website in order for it to have a professional look and feel. To enhance your personal brand, you'll test new ways of conveying your message. <span style="background-color:#4e8d6a;color:white">Moreover, you'll learn how to craft the content that tells everyone what you're all about. Not only will you know how to engage your visitors, but you'll also learn how to be more visible on social media and how to promote your site</span>. In addition, when you realize you need to rank well on Google, you'll also grasp the basic aspects of SEO. Acquiring additional skills will do wonders for your career. - <a href="https://www.topresume.com/career-advice/why-you-need-a-personal-website-asap" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">topresume.com</a></p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="your-personal-branding"><strong>3. Your personal branding</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#your-personal-branding" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><p>Personal branding becomes more and more important. Every time you want the others to know about yourself: who you are, what you are doing, or what you can do, or what your achievements are, etc. <span style="background-color:#4e8d6a;color:white">How much time and energy to do your introduction and people will forget after that</span>. Now, with a personal website, all you need to introduce about yourself is your name card with a name, a title, a brief description and a web address. ✨ Your personal website is not only your digital portfolio, but also a place to express yourself 😎 freely, independently. And when someone else wants to know more deeply about you, they just have to access your website and read all the information provided. Or when you want to share something, compose a new blog post in your website and share that address.</p><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="sharing-knowledge"><strong>4. Sharing knowledge</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#sharing-knowledge" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><blockquote><p>A personal website is also useful for people who want to promote their businesses or share knowledge. If you are a motivational speaker or life coach, for instance, your personal website is a great place to let the world know what you do and how to get in touch with you. In a similar manner to having a portfolio, you can post videos of your past work, as well as a list of your clients, and even positive reviews you have received. - <a href="https://medium.com/digital-marketing-lab/5-important-reasons-why-you-still-need-a-personal-website-d0fba1f51911" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Casey Botticello</a></p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="pre-launching-a-new-product-or-service"><strong>5. Pre-launching a New Product or Service</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#pre-launching-a-new-product-or-service" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><blockquote><p>On a similar note, aspiring sole traders of entrepreneurs can also use personal websites to pre-launch their new business concept, product or service. Such a site can serve multiple purposes, from creating awareness of your developing concept to executing pre-sales and raising much needed revenue <!-- -->[...]<!-- --> Whether you aim to create an overarching brand or simply generate additional income, a personal website can be an invaluable tool. - <a href="https://www.lifehack.org/articles/technology/7-reasons-why-youll-regret-not-having-personal-website-2.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">lifehack.org</a></p></blockquote><h2 class="anchor anchorWithStickyNavbar_LWe7" id="generate-alternative-income"><strong>6. Generate Alternative Income</strong><a class="hash-link" href="#generate-alternative-income" title="Direct link to heading">​</a></h2><blockquote><p>Apart from the branding and generating work, like any website, your personal website can also become a source of secondary income 💰. Based on your website traffic, you can host ads on your site which can make you some good money <code>or providing affiliate links for your visitors</code>. Though you aren't creating your personal website with this intent, it'd be a great add-on if your website designing skills and creative genius end up making a killer personal website. Just imagine, you'd be making money while simultaneously marketing yourself. - <a href="https://www.strikingly.com/content/blog/8-reasons-why-you-must-own-a-personal-website/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">strikingly.com</a></p></blockquote><p><strong>Conclusions</strong></p><blockquote><p>I know you might say, “well, I have Facebook, Instagram, Twitter accounts, etc. and I can promote my work” These are very important social media accounts you should have. But According to this report, there are 3.2 billion searches on Google per day. That's because people are looking for solutions to their problems. Will they find you online? If for example, I am looking for an event management company in Lagos (Nigeria), I will do a Google Search. Google Search Engine will pop up results of companies that have websites as their priority. Having social media accounts is very important but having a personal website adds icing to the cake. - <a href="https://medium.com/your-brand/why-you-need-a-personal-website-5caa661a711" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">labifrancis</a></p></blockquote><p>So, <strong>how to start a personal website?</strong> So many ways to start a personal website. Ari—a serverless website could be a great choice. If you want to start with valuable information and can bring much more value to your visitors than an only impression for the very first time with eye-catching interface, or a lot of animation.</p><p>Wait for my next blog post, <strong><a href="/blog/is-ari-your-choice-to-start-a-personal-website">“Is Ari your choice to start your personal website?”</a></strong>.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Brian Cao</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/chasoft</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="website" term="website"/>
        <category label="personal website" term="personal website"/>
        <category label="new skills" term="new skills"/>
        <category label="sharing" term="sharing"/>
        <category label="knowledge" term="knowledge"/>
    </entry>
</feed>